metrolyrics.com 2010-05-04

# MetroLyrics: Privacy Statement for MetroLyrics and MetroPosts

### MetroLyrics, MetroPosts, and MetroLeap Media Inc. Privacy Statement

#### Introduction

MetroLyrics is a web portal owned by MetroLeap Media Inc.  
MetroPosts is discussion forum owned by MetroLeap Media Inc.

MetroLeap recognizes that your privacy and the protection of your personal information is important to you. This statement discloses how MetroLeap helps protect your personal information while using the MetroLyrics Web Site (www.metrolyrics.com) and its discussion forum MetroPosts (www.metroposts.com). Privacy statement is applicable to both MetroLyrics and MetroPosts, and whenever we refer to MetroLyrics it is applicable to MetroPosts too and vice versa.

MetroLyrics provides lyrics and music information such as albums and artists' biographies, as well as discussion forum to its visitors and members. All lyrics are copyrighted material of artist and/or their representatives. Lyrics are submitted by MetroLyrics' visitors and members, and could be inaccurate or incomplete. Please see MetroLyrics' Terms of Use for more information about MetroLyrics offerings and limitations.

The MetroLyrics Kids Privacy Statement is a separate statement that describes the collection, use and disclosure by MetroLyrics of personal information from or about children and the service for obtaining parental consent.

#### MetroLyrics' collection of your personal information

As described in greater detail below, we collect and process personal information for four primary reasons:

  * to operate an authentication service;
  * to provide you with better services based on your needs, demographic, and region either by MetroLyrics or our partners;
  * to facilitate registration and effective participation at MetroPosts Forum, and
  * to improve security and provide customer support for your MetroLyrics account.
  * What Information Is Collected by MetroLyrics

MetroLyrics collects only that information which is necessary to carry out the four purposes described above. MetroLyrics collects information about your online activity at the web site, such as number of submitted lyrics, in order to select winners in promotions and improve your on-line experience.. If using the Forum, you can select how much of your information will be shared with other members. You can change this information at any time from Forum Control Panel.

When you register with MetroLyrics, you will be asked to provide certain personal information that will be stored in the MetroLyrics Members "profile." As described below, the amount of information requested will vary depending on your preference, where some information will be mandatory in order to register. MetroLyrics Members profile contains, at most, the following personal information: (1) e-mail address, (2) first and last name, (3) country or region, (4) state or territory, (5) ZIP code or postal code, (6) language, (7) time zone, (8) gender, (9) birth date, (10) occupation, and (11) alternate e-mail address.

When you register for your Member's Account, you will be asked to create a password for your account. You may also be requested to provide secret questions and secret answers. You use your secret questions and answers to help verify your identity to MetroLyrics when there are account issues, such as needing to reset your password.

#### MetroLyrics' use of your personal information

### How MetroLyrics Will Not Use Your Personal Information

MetroLyrics will not use or share your personal information in a manner that differs from what is described in this Privacy Statement without your prior consent.

### How MetroLyrics Uses Your Personal Information

MetroLyrics uses your personal information for the operation and maintenance of your account and the MetroLyrics Service. For example, MetroLyrics may use your e-mail address to send you a welcome e-mail message when you first register informing you about the service, telling you how to manage your account. You will receive a separate e-mail to which you must respond in order to validate that you are the owner of the e-mail address associated with your account at MetroLyrics. Failure to respond to the e-mail and verify the address within four days will cause the members account to become inactive. This process is designed to verify the validity of the e-mail address and to help prevent e-mail addresses from being used without permission in the creation of MetroLyrics accounts.

MetroLyrics may also send you e-mail about periodic service or recommended security updates. These periodic e-mails are considered essential to the provision of the service you have requested. You cannot unsubscribe from these mailings. In addition, you may subscribe to receive MetroLyrics e-mail newsletter. You can unsubscribe from this service at any time.

If you need to reset your password and cannot access your primary e-mail account, MetroLyrics may send password reset e-mail to your alternate e-mail address.

#### MetroLyrics' general disclosure of personal information

MetroLyrics occasionally hires other companies to provide limited services on our behalf, such as answering customer support inquiries or performing statistical analyses of our services. MetroLyrics will only provide these companies with those pieces of your personal information needed to deliver the services, and the companies and their employees are prohibited from using that personal information for any other purpose.

MetroLyrics may provide your e-mail address to our partners to be used at their discretion. This may be done only if you allowed us to do so. Your approval is done by checking the form box stating clearly that you allow us to share your e-mail, which could be done either during the registration process or from your account control panel.

MetroLyrics may disclose personal information if required to do so by law or in the good-faith belief that such action is necessary to: (a) conform to legal requirements or comply with legal process served on MetroLyrics; (b) protect and defend the rights or property of MetroLyrics; or (c) act under exigent circumstances to protect the personal safety of users of the MetroLyrics' Service, or the public.

### Your MetroLyrics Profile Information

You can choose the type of information in your MetroLyrics profile to share with other members and general public on the MetroLyrics' Forum. You can also choose how much of your information we can share with our partners. You can use the check boxes on the 'Your MetroLyrics Profile' page to choose whether to share your e-mail address, your name, and/or the non-identifiable profile information, such as country.

### Use of Shared Information by MetroLyrics' Partners

MetroLyrics' partners that we shared information with can use it for a variety of purposes. These can include personalizing your experience at their sites. MetroLyrics partners may share your personal information and/or unique identifier with third parties in order to fulfill a service or transaction you may have requested. In addition, they may send you unsolicited offerings based on your profile. If sending you unsolicited offering, they have the obligation to include instructions on how to take you off of their communication in the future, should you decide to do so.

#### Managing your personal information

### Access to Your Personal Information

You can always add, update, or make other changes to the information in your MetroLyrics profile.

### Closing Your MetroLyrics Account

You may close your MetroLyrics account at any time by going to MetroLyrics Member Services and clicking Close my MetroLyrics account, or by contacting MetroLyrics customer support

If you attempt to register for a MetroLyrics account and find that someone else has already created a MetroLyrics account with your e-mail address, you have the option of contacting MetroLyrics customer service and requesting that the MetroLyrics account using your e-mail address be forced to change so that you may use your e-mail address as your Account.

#### Security and storage of your personal information

MetroLyrics is committed to protecting the security of your personal information. We use a variety of security technologies and procedures to help protect your personal information from unauthorized access, use, or disclosure.

You must type the correct password to access your MetroLyrics information. It is your responsibility to ensure the security of your MetroLyrics account password and not to reveal this information to others.

Personal information collected by MetroLyrics may be stored and processed in Canada, the United States or any other country in which MetroLyrics or its affiliates, subsidiaries, or agents maintain facilities. By using the MetroLyrics Service, you consent to any such transfer of information outside of your country.

#### Lyrics copyright

Lyrics posted in metrolyrics.com database are either copyrighted or in public domain. Lyrics may be in public domain if their owners decided to make them available to public, or if lyrics are old enough to become public domain. Most of the lyrics however are not in the public domain. Lyrics posted on metrolyrics.com are copyright of their rightful owners. We receive lyrics directly from Labels, Independent Artists, and from site visitors. All lyrics are posted in our database unless specifically requested by rightful copyright owners not to include them in our database. We believe that there is mutual interest to all parties to have lyrics posted in metrolyrics.com. Music listeners do not make decision not to purchase a song if they have read the lyrics. On the contrary, they may decide to purchase the song if they liked lyrics. Labels and artists get more exposure to their work, and more sales as direct result of content posted on metrolyrics.com. There is a link from all lyrics pages to purchase music CD from amazon.com, contributing directly to hundreds of CDs purchased with referrals from metrolyrics.com. Some label companies, realizing the value of MetroLyrics, provide lyrics to their newest releases or debut artists to get maximum exposure in short time. If you hold the publishing rights to any music and would like to include lyrics in our database, please contact us to grant a license for inclusion. We will pay you for the lyrics inclusion in our database. We are actively pursuing labels, music publishers, and lyrics copyright holders to license their lyrics for inclusion in our database. If on the other hand, you see lyrics in our database that you hold licensing rights for AND DO NOT WANT THEM INCLUDED in our database, contact us to exclude the lyrics from the database.

#### Use of cookies

A cookie is a very small text file that a Web site saves to your computer's hard disk to store information that you provide about yourself or to store your preferences.

MetroLyrics uses cookies whenever you sign in to a MetroLyrics site. MetroLyrics stores your unique identifier, the time you signed in, and whatever MetroLyrics profile information you have chosen to share with our partners, in an encrypted cookie on your hard disk. This cookie allows you to move from page to page without having to sign in again on each page.

MetroLyrics also uses cookies to improve the sign in experience. For example, MetroLyrics may store your e-mail address in a cookie that will remain on your computer after you sign out. This cookie allows your e-mail address to be pre-populated, so that you will only need to type your password the next time you sign in.
